给洛斯 圣诞快乐
——爱你的妈妈
关掉收音机
Turn that down!
关掉 史蒂夫 关掉
Turn it off! Steve-o, turn it off.
乔 安静
Joe, shut up!
洛斯
Rose!
米奇
Mickey!
杰琪 是塔迪斯
Jackie, it's the TARDIS!
我知道 我听到了
I know, I heard it!
她还活着
She's alive, Mickey!
我早就说过她还活着
I said so, didn't I? She's alive!
先别说话
Shut up a minute.
她在哪里
Where is it, then?
我们到了 伦敦 地球
Here we are, then. London, Earth,
太阳系 我成功了
the Solar System. I did it!
杰琪 米奇 天呐
Jackie! Mickey! Blimey!
不不不 等一等
No, no, no, hold on.
慢着 我想说什么呢
Wait there. What was I gonna say?
我有件事要告诉你们
There was something I had to tell you,
一件很重要的事 是什么
something important. What was it? Hold on, hold on.
等等
Hold on. Shh.
我知道了
Oh! I know!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
怎么了 他没事吧
What happened? Is he all right?
不知道 他就这么倒下了
I dunno, he just keeled over.
他是谁 博士呢
But where's the Doctor?
那就是他
That's him.
就在你面前
Right in front of you.
他就是博士
That's the Doctor.
什么意思 他就是博士
What d'you mean, "That's the Doctor"?
哪个博士
Doctor who?
神秘博士2005圣诞特别篇
圣诞入侵
好了
Here we go.
蒂娜有一个房客 是学医的
Tina the Cleaner's got this lodger, medical student,
我趁她睡着时拿来的
and she was fast asleep, so I just took it.
我还是觉得应该送他去医院
I still say we should take him to a hospital.
不行 他们会把他关起来的
They'd lock him up.
还会解剖他
They'd dissect him.
他的一瓶血液就能改变人类的未来
One bottle of his blood could change the future of the human race.
别说了
Now shush!
两个都很正常
Both working.
什么意思 两个
What d'you mean, "both"?
他有两颗心脏
He's got two hearts. Oh,
别傻了
don't be stupid.
他确实有
He has.
他还有什么有两个
Anything else he's got two of?
别烦他
Leave him alone!
他怎么能改变面孔
How can he go changing his face?
只是外表变了 还是人也不同了
Is that a different face or is he a different person?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
对不起
Sorry.
问题是 我以为我了解他 妈妈
The thing is... I thought I knew him, Mum.
以为我们
I thought me and him were...
然后他就变成这样
Then he goes and does this.
我老是忘记他不是人类
I keep forgetting he's not human.
重点是
The big question is,
你从哪里弄来男人睡衣的
where did you get a pair of men's pajamas from?!
霍华德偶尔会来过夜
Howard's been staying over.
什么 市场那个霍华德
What? Howard from the market?
你们交往多久了
How long's that been going on?
大概一个月
A month or so.
一开始他把货送来家门口
First, he starts delivering to the door.
我就觉得奇怪了
I thought, "That's odd."
然后他送了一袋橙子
Next thing you know, there's a bag of oranges...
那是哈丽叶特·琼斯吗
Is that Harriet Jones?
算了吧
Never mind me!
她为什么上电视了
Why's she on telly?
她当上首相了
She's Prime Minister now!
我的周薪涨了18镑
I'm 18 quid a week better off.
大家称之为英国的黄金时代
They're calling it Britain's golden age.
我常说我家洛斯见过她
I keep on saying, "My Rose has met her."
不仅如此
Did more than that.
还和她一起阻止了第三次世界大战
Stopped World War Three with her.
哈丽叶特·琼斯
Harriet Jones.
首相 有人说古尼维尔一号太空探索器
What about those calling the Guinevere One Space Probe
是浪费金钱
a waste of money?
这种想法就错了
That's where you thought wrong.
我完全无法同意
I completely disagree.
古尼维尔一号是这个国家雄心壮志的象征
The Guinevere One Space Probe represents this country's limitless ambition.
英国的杰作在恒星间漫游
British workmanship, sailing up there among the stars.
这是圣诞节的精神
This is the spirit of Christmas,
是诞生 欢庆和新时代的来临
birth, and rejoicing, and the dawn of a new age.
那正是我们所做到的
That is what we're achieving,
五千里之外 活动着人类自己的奇迹
50 million miles away. Our very own miracle!
无人驾驶的探索器即将降落
The unmanned probe Guinevere One is about to make its final descent.
今天午夜应该就能接收到火星的照片
Photographs of the Martian landscape should be received by midnight tonight.
你要20磅干什么
What d'you need, 20 quid?
我会还给你的
D'you mind? I'll pay you back.
就当是圣诞礼物吧
Call it a Christmas present.
天呐 我就像与世隔绝了似的
God, I'm all out of synch.
一旦进了塔迪斯你就会忘记圣诞节这些事情
You just forget about Christmas and things in the TARDIS.
这些都不存在
They don't exist.
让人失去时间观念
You get sort of...timeless.
真有趣
That's fascinating!
我最爱听塔迪斯的故事了
I love hearing stories about the TARDIS!
继续 再说一个
Go on, tell us another,
听一天也不会厌倦 塔迪斯这个 塔迪斯那个
I could listen to it all day! TARDIS this, TARDIS that...
住口
Shut up!
有一次 塔迪斯降落在黄色大花园里
Ooh, and one time, the TARDIS landed in a big yellow garden,
那里充满汽球
full of balloons!
我没有这样 -你有
I'm not like that! You so are!
我快把你逼疯了吧
Must drive you mad.
想不到你还没有放弃我
Surprised you don't give up on me.
这就是重点 你能依靠我
That's the thing, isn't it? You can rely on me.
我可不会改头换面
I don't go changing my face.
对
Yeah.
万一他快死了怎么办 -够了
What if he's dying? OK...
对不起
Sorry!
就让我们好好过圣诞节
Just let it be Christmas.
可以吗 就这一会儿
Can you do that? Just for a bit?
你和我过圣诞
You, me and Christmas.
没有博士 没有怪物 没有你死我活
No Doctor, no bog-monsters, no life or death.
好
OK.
你保证 -我保证
Promise? Yes!
对了 你要给你妈买什么礼物
Right. What are you gonna get for your mum?
我这几天一直就在附近
I'm round there all the time now.
有次周末她给我弄晚餐
She does my dinner on a Sunday.
整个下午一直在念叨你…
She talks about you all afternoon. Yap, yap, yap, yap...
是我们
It's us!
他们在追我们
They're after us.
怎么回事 我们做了什么 他们为什么要追我们
What's going on? What have we done? Why are they after us?!
出租车
Taxi!
他们要追的是博士
They're after the Doctor.
跟你逛个街都会被铜管乐队袭击
I can't even go shopping with you! We get attacked by a brass band!
你打电话给谁
Who are you phoning?
我妈妈
My mum.
她突然回来 也没打声招呼 我什么都没买
She turns up, no warning, I've got nothing in.
我说 如果你圣诞晚宴想吃罐头
I said, "Rose, if you want a Christmas dinner of meat paste,
那随便你
then so be it..."
快挂电话
Get off the phone!
那些圣诞老人是谁
Who were those Santa things?
不知道
I dunno,
但他们要对付我们
but think about it. They were after us.
我们有什么重要的 没有
What's important about us? Nothing,
除了躺在家里的博士
except we've got the Doctor!
别过来
No, don't come round.
我家乱得很
The flat's all topsy-turvy.
她突然冲回来 家里弄的乱糟糟的
She just barges in and litters the place.
那我节礼日来看你吧
Yeah, I'll come and see you Boxing Day.
快挂电话
Get off the phone!
是贝芙 她跟你问好
It's only Bev. She says hello.
贝芙 恐怕你得等一等
Bev? Look, it'll have to wait.
这里不安全 我们必须离开
It's not safe. We've gotta get out.
我们能去哪儿
Where can we go?
我朋友斯坦那里有地方
My mate Stan will put us up.
离这儿太近了
That's only two streets away.
小茉住在哪里
Where's Mo now?
不知道 山峰区吧
I dunno, the Peak District.
好 我们去小茉表姐家
We'll go to Cousin Mo's, then.
今天是平安夜 我们哪里都不去
It's Christmas Eve, we're not going anywhere!
你到底在胡说什么
What are you babbling about?
妈妈
Mum.
那棵圣诞树哪来的
Where did you get that tree?
那是新的 你从哪儿弄来的
That's a new tree. Where did you get it?
我以为是你送来的
I thought it was you.
怎么可能是我
How can it be me?
你们去逛街 后来门铃响了
You went shopping. There was a ring at the door,
树就在外面了
and there it was.
不是我放的
That wasn't me.
那么是谁
Then who was it?
不是吧
You're kidding me.
走 快走
Go, go! Get out!
我们得去救博士
We've gotta save the Doctor.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
不能扔下他
We can't leave him.
米奇
Mickey!
别管它了 出去 出去
Leave it. Get out, get out!
米奇 快走
Get out of there!
别管了 留下他吧 -快进来
No, leave him, just leave him. Get in here!
博士 快醒醒
Doctor, wake up!
我要被圣诞树杀死了
I'm gonna get killed by a Christmas tree!
帮帮我
Help me.
远程遥控的
Remote control.
是谁在控制它呢
But who's controlling it?
是他们 他们是什么
That's them. What are they?
他们走了
They've just gone!
这是什么废物东西
What kind of rubbish were they?
恕我直言 音速起子就能吓跑
No offense. They're not much cop
肯定不是什么厉害东西
if a sonic screwdriver scares them off.
试水鱼 -什么
Pilot fish. What?
他们只是试水鱼
They were just pilot fish. Aaargh!
怎么了
What's wrong?
你太早叫醒我
You woke me up too soon.
我还在重生 正在释放能量
I'm still regenerating. I'm bursting with energy.
看到吗
You see?
试水鱼在几百万里外就能嗅到
The pilot fish could smell it, a million miles away,
所以他们要削弱我的防御
so they eliminate the defense
也就是你们 然后捉走我
- you lot - then carry me off.
我的能量可以够他们用个好几年的
They could run their batteries off me for a couple of years...
我的头
My head!
我的神经元正在内爆
I'm having a neuron implosion.
我需要… -你需要什么
I need... What d'you need?
我需要… -说吧 告诉我
I need... Tell me.
我需要… -止痛药
I need... Painkillers?
阿斯匹灵 可待因 扑热息痛
D'you need aspirin? I need... Codeine?
还是胃药 液态石蜡
Paracetamol? Pepto-Bismol?
维生素 维C 维D 维E
Liquid paraffin? Vitamin C? Vitamin D? Vitamin E?
食物 简单的东西
Is it food? Something simple?
一碗汤 一碗热汤
A bowl of soup? A nice bowl of soup.
汤和三文治 汤和火腿三文治
Soup and a sandwich? Soup and a little ham sandwich?
我需要你安静一会儿
I need you to shut up.
看来他一点都没变 对吧
He hasn't changed that much, has he?
我们时间不多
We haven't got much time.
如果外面有试水鱼
If there's pilot fish, then...
为什么我睡衣口袋里会有苹果
Why's there an apple in my dressing gown?
那是霍华德的 抱歉
That's Howard, sorry.
他把苹果放在睡衣里
He keeps apples in his dressing gown?
以防肚子饿
He gets hungry.
他睡着了也会肚子饿
He gets hungry in his sleep?
有时会
Sometimes.
我的脑袋正在崩溃
Brain, collapsing!
但是试水鱼
But the pilot fish...
试水鱼意味着 某种…
The pilot fish mean that something...
某种…
Something...
某种东西要来了
Something's coming.
杰琪 我用用电话线行吗
Jackie, I'm using the phone line. Is that OK?
行 记下用了多少
Keep account of it.
现在是午夜
It's midnight.
圣诞节到了 -有好转吗
Christmas Day. Any change?
情况更糟了 只有一个心脏在跳动
He's worse. Just one heart beating.
负责英国登陆火星的科学家
Scientists in charge of Britain's mission to Mars
成功跟古尼维尔一号重新取得联系
have re-established contact with the Guinevere One Space Probe.
希望几分钟后收到星球表面的首个传送
They're expecting the first transmission from the planet in the next few minutes.
是的 我们回到正轨了
We're back on schedule.
收到古尼维尔一号的讯号
We've received a signal from Guinevere One.
看来已经成功登陆火星
The Mars landing would seem to be an unqualified success.
不久前完全失去联系是真的吗
Is it true you completely lost contact earlier tonight?
是的 我们也吓了一跳
Yes, we had a bit of a scare.
古尼维尔一号失去了踪影
Guinevere seemed to fall off the scope,
但只是一小会儿
but it was just a blip,
只失联了几秒钟
only disappeared for a few seconds.
她现在没事了 绝对没问题
She's fine now, absolutely fine.
我们随时能收到即时图片
We're getting the first pictures, transmitted live, any minute now.
我最好还是先回去 谢谢
I'd better get back to it, thanks.
查到了 试水鱼
Here we go, pilot fish.
他们是食腐动物 正如博士所说
They're scavengers, like he said.
他们小而无害
Harmless, they're just tiny.
不过他们身边的大鱼
But the little fish swim alongside the big fish.
例如鲨鱼
D'you mean like sharks?
大型鲨鱼
Big sharks.
博士的意思是他们来了
The Doctor means we've had them,
大家伙也就不远了
now we get that.
有东西正在前来
Something is coming.
有多接近
How close?
不知道
I don't know,
但试水鱼不会离开大鱼很远
but the pilot fish don't swim far from the daddy.
那就是很近
So it's close?
好怪的岩石
Funny sort of rocks.
那不是岩石
That's not rocks.
外星生物的脸通过实时传输出现在BBC1频道
A face of an alien life form was transmitted live on BBC One tonight
十二月25日
On the 25th of December,
人类看到外星生命存在的铁证
the human race has been shown absolute proof that alien life exists.
全球都能看到这些惊人的影像
These remarkable images have been relayed across the world.
请这边走
This way, sir.
利维先生
Mr Llewellyn.
利维先生来了 长官
Mr Llewellyn, ma'am.
我是首相 哈丽叶特·琼斯
Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
我知道你是谁
Yes, I know who you are.
看来我破坏你的圣诞节了
Suppose I've ruined your Christmas.
我从不下班 我们已经发布了掩盖说辞
Never off duty. Now, we've put out a cover story,a
艾力克正处理
Alex has been handling it.
我们解释说是一个恶作剧
We've said it was a hoax,
是面具和假体装扮的
We've said it was a hoax, some sort of mask or prosthetics,
说是学生劫持了频道之类的
students hijacking the signal, that sort of thing.
艾力克是我的得力助手
Alex is my right-hand man.
虽然不习惯有助手 但我很喜欢
I'm not used to having a right-hand man. I quite like it, though.
我也是
So do I.
我看这绝不是恶作剧吧
I don't suppose there is any chance it was a hoax?
如果只是那样 我们都可以回家了
That would be nice. Then we could all go home.
没有人给你倒杯咖啡吧
I don't suppose anyone's offered you a coffee?
没有
Um, no.
传送是真的
The transmission was genuine.
他们似乎是新的外星品种
And this seems to be a new species of alien.
至少不是上次遇到的种类
At least, not one we've encountered before.
你似乎已经对外星人习以为常了
You seem to be talking about aliens as a matter of fact.
国会禁止我出版自传是有原因的
There's an Act of Parliament banning my autobiography.
首相 -马上来
Prime Minister? I'm with you.
雅各布小姐会跟你解释
Miss Jacobs can explain.
我们没见过面 我是哈丽叶特·琼斯
We haven't been introduced. Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
我知道你是谁
Yes, I know who you are.
讯号不是来自火星表面
The transmission didn't come from the surface of Mars.
是在火星五千里的上方传过来的
Guinevere One was broadcasting from a point 5,000 miles above the planet.
换句话说 他们有太空船
In other words, they've got a ship,
还劫持了我们的探索器
and the probe is on board.
如果讯号不是来自火星表面
But if they're not from the surface,
那么他们可能不是来自火星
they might not be from Mars.
他们也许不是火星人
Maybe they're not actual Martians.
当然了 火星人外表截然不同
Of course not. Martians look completely different.
我们认为太空船飞行时遇到探索器
We think the ship was in flight when they just came across the probe.
他们还在移动
And they're moving.
太空船还在航行
The ship's still in flight now.
哈伯天线阵侦测到的
It's on the Hubble Array.
向哪个方向移动 -地球
Moving in which direction? Towards us.
有多快 -很快
How fast? Very fast.
你叫什么名字 -莎丽
What was your name again? Sally.
谢谢你 莎丽
Thank you, Sally.
洛斯
Rose!
看看 我进入了军方的电脑
Take a look. I've got access to the military.
他们正追踪太空船
They're tracking a spaceship.
飞船很大 正在迅速飞向地球
It's big, fast and coming this way.
他们想要什么
Coming for what?
博士
The Doctor?!
不知道 也许是冲人类来的呢
I don't know. Maybe it's coming for all of us.
见过他们吗
Have you seen them before?
没有
No.
翻译软件
Translation software.
好的
Yes, sir.
我不明白他们在说什么
I don't understand what they're saying.
塔迪斯会在我大脑里翻译外星语言
The TARDIS translates alien languages, inside my head,
不论何时何地
all the time, wherever I am.
为什么现在不起作用呢
So why isn't it doing it now?
不知道 大概跟博士有关
I dunno. Must be the Doctor.
也许他是线路中重要的一环
Like he's part of the circuit, and he's...
现在断了
he's broken.
我接到华盛顿的要求
I'm getting demands from Washington, ma'am.
美国总统坚持要接管大局
The President is insisting that he takes control of the situation.
你联络总统 照我的话说
You can tell the President, and please use these exact words,
他不是我的上司
he's not my boss,
我决不会允许他把这变成战争
and he's certainly not turning this into a war.
有什么进展
What have we got?
还没有
Nothing yet.
翻译外星语言需要时间
Translating an alien language is going to take time.
太空船距离地球多远
How far off is the ship?
约五小时
About five hours.
虽然声称是一个骗局
Despite claims of an alien hoax,
但据报导北约军队已经进入警戒状态
it's been reported that NATO forces are on red alert.
拜托了 亲爱的 你需要什么
Come on, sweetheart. What do you need?
你需要什么 告诉我
What is it you need? Tell me.
据政府消息来源说
Speaking strictly off the record,
这将是我们最漫长的一夜
government sources are calling this our longest night.
我们还没有发现九号吗
I don't suppose we've had a Code Nine?
还找不到博士
No sign of the Doctor?
没有消息
Nothing yet.
你见过他吧
You've met him, haven't you?
他是一个传奇人物
More like the stuff of legend.
对
He is that.
但找不到他
Failing him...
火炬木能帮我们吗
What about Torchwood?
我明白我原本不应该知道这个
I'm not supposed to know about it, I realise that.
连联合国都不知道
Not even the UN knows.
但我们现在需要火炬木的帮助
But if ever there was a need for Torchwood, it's now.
我负不了这个责
I can't take responsibility.
我负责
I can.
快去办 叫他们准备
See to it. Get them ready.
首相
Prime Minister?
怎样
Has it worked?
快行了
Just about.
"人类" 也可能翻译为"牛"
"People," that could be cattle,
你们属于我们
"you belong to us,
属于西格拉克斯
to the Sycorax."
他们自称西格拉克斯 不是火星人
They seem to be called Sycorax, not Martians.
我们拥有你们
"We own you.
拥有你们的土地 矿物和宝石
We now possess your land, your minerals, your precious stones.
你们必须投降 不然他们就没命
"You will surrender or they will die.
西格拉克斯强壮 西格拉克斯伟大
Sycorax strong, Sycorax mighty.
西格拉克斯…石头
Sycorax rock,"
按现代语境 就是他们"很牛"的意思
as in the modern sense, "They rock!"
"他们"会没命
"THEY will die."
不是"你们"会没命 他们是指谁
Not "YOU will die," "THEY will die." Who's they?
不知道 但是代词没有翻译错 确实是"他们"
I don't know, but it is the right personal pronoun. It's "they".
给他们回复
Send them a reply.
告诉他们 今天是地球和平的一天
Tell them this is a day of peace on Planet Earth.
我们想把和平扩展到西格拉克斯
Tell them we extend that peace to the Sycorax.
还告诉他们
And then tell them
地球有武器 我们绝不会投降
this planet is armed, and we do not surrender.
博士不会这样做
The Doctor wouldn't do this,
从前的博士 真正的博士 他会醒来
the old Doctor, the proper Doctor. He'd wake up.
然后拯救我们
He'd save us.
你真的很爱他 是吧
You really love him, don't you?
他们收到消息了 马上就会回复了
They got the message. Here comes the response.
那是什么
What was that?
是某种回复吗
Was that a reply?
不知道 似乎是某种能量
I don't know. Looked like some sort of energy,
或者静电
or static?
几乎就像谁在下咒语
Almost like someone casting a spell.
可能是另一种语言
Maybe it's a different form of language,
表意字或象形文字
some sort of ideogram or pictogram, or...
怎么了
What the hell?
是那种光 是相同的光
It's the light. It's the same light.
莎丽 你在干什么 莎丽
Sally? What are you doing? Sally?
别动手 你会伤到她的
Leave her, you'll hurt her.
让他们过去 -他们在干什么
Let them pass! Where are they going?
你怎么了 杰森
What is wrong with you? Jason?
杰森
Jason?!
桑德拉
Sandra!
他不听我的 一直走不肯停
He won't listen. He's just walking. He won't stop walking.
身上有种奇怪的光
There's a sort of light thing.
杰森 停住
Jason! Stop it!
快点停下
Right now.
他们全往同一个方向走
They're all heading in the same direction.
只是某些人受影响
But it's only certain people.
为什么我们没事
Why isn't it affecting us?
首相 全国各地都受影响
It's happening all over the country.
艾伦 给我站住 这不好玩
Alan, stop this! It's not funny any more.
艾伦 回到屋里
Come back inside the house!
凯伦 听妈妈说 马上回去
Catrin, listen to Mummy, come back inside now.
乔纳森 跟妈妈回去
And you Jonathan! Come back in with Mummy.
乔纳森 跟妈妈回去 你们吓死我了
Jonathan! You're scaring me now, come on!
艾伦 快来帮帮忙
Alan, help me out here, please!
按照目前的情形 他们似乎在前往任何高楼大厦
As far as I can tell, they're heading for any sort of high-rise building.
任何有台阶 有楼梯的建筑
Anything with stairs, anything with steps.
他们一直往上走
They're going all the way up.
他们要上天台
They're going to the roof.
我正赶到建筑面前 他们有好几百人
Just making my way to the front of the building. There's hundreds of them.
我的天呐 他们一直走到边缘
Oh, my God, they're going right up to the edge.
他们要跳下去 全都是
They're all gonna jump!
莎丽 站住
Sally, stop it!
我是丹尼 丹尼·利维
It's Danny Llewellyn, Daniel Llewellyn.
莎丽 集中精神 听我说
Sally, just concentrate. listen to me.
你被控制了
You're being controlled.
我们需要你
We need you.
站住 莎丽
Stop it, Sally!
杰森 我在跟你说话
Jason, I'm talking to you.
停下来
Just stop!
不仅是英国
It's not just the whole country.
全世界都一样
It's the whole world.
他们停下来了 全停下来了
They've stopped. They've all stopped.
他们就只是站着 站在天台边缘
They're just standing there. Right on the edge.
报告说有三分一人受影响
According to reports, it's like a third.
全球三分一人口
One third of the world's population,
20亿人准备纵身跃下
two billion people, ready to jump.
投降否则他们没命
Surrender or they will die.
我们应该怎么办
What do we do?
没办法
Nothing.
没有人能救我们 再也没有了
There's no-one to save us. Not any more.
等等 有一种规律
Wait a minute. There is a pattern.
他们全都是父子 母子
All these people tend to be father and son, mother and daughter,
兄弟姐妹 是家人
brothers and sisters. Family groups,
但是没有夫妇
but not husbands and wives.
天呐 是古尼维尔一号
Oh, my God. It's Guinevere One.
你们有所有员工的医疗档案吗
Have you got medical records for all your staff?
当然有
Of course we have, yes.
火炬木有什么回应
What about Torchwood?
他们还在努力
Still working on it.
别忘了他们也刚失去三分一人员
Bear in mind, they just lost a third of their staff.
但是他们有我们需要的东西吧
But they do have what we need?
有
Yes, ma'am.
叫他们快点
Tell them to hurry up.
找到了 莎丽·雅各布的血型是A+
Here it is! Sally Jacobs, blood group, A Positive.
还有谁出去了
Who else walked out?
卢克·帕森斯
Luke Parsons.
卢克·帕森斯 A+
Luke Parsons, A Positive!
杰弗瑞·巴斯特
Geoffrey Baxter.
巴斯特 A+ 对了
Baxter, A Positive. That's it.
他们全是A+血型
They're all A Positive.
全球有多少人是A+血型
How many people in the world are A Positive?
不知道
No idea,
但我打赌是三分之一
but I bet it's one third.
这血型有什么特别的
What's so special about that blood group?
没什么 但是 都是我的错
Nothing, but... It's my fault.
古尼维尔一号上 有一块标示人类的金属板
Guinevere One, it's got one of those plaques, identifying the human race.
给各恒星的讯息
A message to the stars.
我没想过会起什么效用
You don't expect anything to come of it,
但我放了地图 音乐 样本
but I put on maps and music and samples.
包括小麦种子 水 和血液
There's wheat seeds and water and... And blood.
A+型的血液
A Positive.
西格拉克斯有一瓶A+型血液
The Sycorax have got a vial of A Positive,
我不知道其中原理 但有了那个
and, I don't know how, but through that...
他们控制了那种血型
They control the blood.
天呐
Oh, my God.
只有一个办法了
There's only one more thing I can try.
少校 跟我来
Major! With me!
各位
Ladies and gentlemen,
请听我在这可怕时刻说几句
if I may take a moment during this terrible time.
这不是女王讲话 恐怕那个取消了
It's hardly the Queen's speech. I'm afraid that's been canceled.
皇室人员怎么样了
Did we ask about the Royal Family?
他们在天台上
Oh... they're on the roof.
各位 这次危机很特别
But, ladies and gentlemen, this crisis is unique,
恐怕情况会越来越严重
and I'm afraid to say it might get much worse.
请你们保持镇定
I would ask you all to remain calm.
但我有一个请求
But I have one request.
博士 如果你在的话
Doctor? If you're out there,
我们需要你
we need you.
我不知道应该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
如果你听得到 博士
If you can hear me, Doctor,
如果有人认识博士或能找到他
if anyone knows the Doctor, if anyone can find him,
这次的情况前所未有地困难
the situation has never been more desperate.
帮帮我们 求你 博士 救我们
Help us. Please, Doctor, help us.
他离开了
He's gone.
博士离开了
The Doctor's gone.
他离开了我 妈妈
He's left me, Mum.
Left me, Mum.
音速波 是太空船进入大气层了
Sonic wave! It's the spaceship, it's hit the atmosphere!
米奇 我们要带他走
Mickey, we're gonna carry him.
妈妈 去拿食物 我们要走
Mum, get your stuff, and get some food, we're going.
去哪里
Where to?
塔迪斯 那里是唯一安全的地方
The TARDIS. It's the only safe place.
我们去那里做什么 -躲起来
What are we gonna do in there? Hide.
就这样
Is that it?
妈妈 看看天空
Look in the sky.
有外星人入侵
There's a great big alien invasion
我不知道应该怎么办
and I don't know what to do, OK?
我跟他一起旅行 见过许多东西
I've travelled with him and seen all that stuff,
但回到家后却一点用都没有
but when I'm stuck at home, I'm useless.
我们只能逃跑躲藏
All we can do is run and hide,
对不起
and I'm sorry.
马上去
Now move!
他们在传送讯息 看屏幕
They're transmitting. On screen.
请这世界的领袖站出来
"Will the leader of this world stand forward?"
我很骄傲能代表地球
I'm proud to represent this planet.
上来
"Come aboard!"
怎么上来
How do I do that?
怎么了
What's happening?
我猜这就是远距传送
I would imagine it's called a teleport.
是头盔 他们可能和我们一样
It's a helmet. They might be like us!
也许不是
Or not.
妈妈 放下那些 帮帮我们
Mum, will you leave that stuff and give us a hand?
是食物 你说我们需要食物
It's food. You said we need...
赶紧放下
Just leave it!
你们必须投降
"You will surrender,
否则我就发出最后的…诅咒
or I will release the final curse,
你们的人会跳下来
"and your people will jump."
容我说几句
If I can speak...
利维先生 你只是平民
Mr Llewellyn, you're a civilian.
不 探测器是我发射的
No. I sent out the probe,
我跟他们建立了联系
I made contact with these people.
这是我的责任
This whole thing's my responsibility.
容我直言
With respect, sir.
人类正踏出迈向宇宙的第一步
The human race is taking its first step towards the stars,
但跟你相比 我们只是小孩子
but we are like children, compared to you.
需要帮助的小孩子
Children who need help.
需要同情
Children who need compassion.
我求你展示同情之心
I beg of you now. Show that compassion.
他是你的囚犯
That man was your prisoner!
你们也应该有战争法则 禁止…
Even your species must have Articles of War forbidding...
我是首相哈丽叶特·琼斯
Harriet Jones, Prime Minister.
我们知道你是谁
"Yes, we know who you are."
投降 不然他们就没命
"Surrender or they will die."
如果我投降
If I do surrender,
情况有什么改善
how would that be better?
一半卖作奴隶 或者三分之一送命
"One half is sold into slavery "or one third dies.
你选吧
"Your choice."
你不会开这个吗
No chance you could fly this thing?
不会了
Not any more. No.
你以前会
You did it before.
对 但那段记忆好像被抹掉了
I know, but it's sort of been wiped out of my head, like it's forbidden.
如果我再试 恐怕宇宙会被撕裂
If I try it again, I think the universe rips in half.
那还是算了
Better not, then.
对
Maybe not.
我们做什么 就光坐着吗
What do we do? Just sit here?
顶多只能这样了
That's as good as it gets.
来吧 喝杯茶
Here we go, nice cup of tea.
好一个解决办法
Oh, the solution to everything!
别再抱怨了
Stop your moaning.
我去拿其他食物来
I'll get the rest of the food.
喝茶 世界快灭亡了 我们竟然在野餐
Tea! It's like we're having a picnic, while the world comes to an end.
真够英国风格
Very British.
这个怎么用
How does this thing work?
能看电视的话我们就能看到外面的情况
If it picks up TV, maybe we can see what's going on.
我们可能已投降了
Maybe we've surrendered.
怎么启动
What d'you do to it?
不知道 会自动调节的
It sort of tunes itself.
那噪音 那个滴滴声
The noise, the bleeping,
他们说是机器声音 外来机器
they say it's machinery. Foreign machinery.
他们指控我们藏有机器
They're accusing us of hiding it,
有阴谋
conspiring...
搬上来
Bring it on board!
洛斯
Rose?
Rose!
可能是求救讯号
Maybe it's a distress signal.
那又能有什么用呢
For lot of good that's gonna do.
你要一直这样没精打采吗
Are you gonna be a misery all the time?
是
Yes.
替我设想一下
Look at it from my point of view.
被迫吃你妈煮的东西
Stuck in here with your mum's cooking!
她在哪里
Where is she?
我还是去帮帮她
I'd better give her a hand.
外面可能正枪林弹雨
It might start raining missiles out there.
跟她说带罐头就好了
Tell her anything from a tin, that's fine.
你为什么不自己告诉她
Why don't you tell her yourself?
我没这个胆量
I'm not that brave.
我可不同意
Oh, I dunno.
洛斯
Rose!
放开我
Get off! Get off me!
门 快关门
The door. Close the door!
洛斯 别怕有我在
Rose! Rose! I've got you!
天啊 可爱的孩子
My Lord, oh,my precious baby.
博士
The Doctor.
他和你们在一起吗
Is he with you.
没有
No.
只有我们
We're on our own.
这金发女孩 她有那个蓝盒子
"The yellow girl. She has the clever blue box.
因此她替你们的星球作主
"Therefore, she speaks for your planet."
她不能 -我能
But she can't. Yeah, I can.
不要
Don't you dare.
总要有人来当博士
Someone's gotta be the Doctor.
他们会杀掉你 -不去照样会被杀
They'll kill you. Never stopped him.
我跟西格拉克斯对话
I er... I address the Sycorax...
根据《影子宣言》第15章
.according to Article 15 of the Shadow Proclamation.
我命令你们离开地球
I command you to leave this world,
我代表…
with all the authority of
拉萨哥利哥法拿巴托里斯的斯利辛国会
the Slitheen Parliament of Raxacoricofallapa-torious,
格尔斯联盟的权力…
the Gelth Confederacy...
授予我权利…
as... sanctioned...
伟大的加戈菲斯
by the Mighty Jagrafess and...
还有戴立克
Ooh, the Daleks!
马上和平地离开地球
Now leave this planet in peace! In peace.
你真幽默
"You are very, very funny.
现在你要没命
"And now you're going to die."
别碰她 -别伤害她
Leave her alone! Don't touch her!
你自以为很聪明
"Did you think you were clever
胡扯一通
"with your stolen words?"
我们是西格拉克斯 我们统领着黑暗
"We are the Sycorax. We stride the darkness.
跟我们相比 你们只是哭闹的孩子
"Next to us, you are but a wailing child.
如果你已是地球最出色的人选
"If you are the best your planet can offer as a champion..."
那你们的世界注定灭亡
Then your world will be gutted...
地球人将成为奴隶
and your people enslaved.
慢着 那是英语
Hold on, that's English.
他在说英语 -你在说英语
He's talking English. You're talking English.
我绝不会屈尊使用你们落后的语言
I would never dirty my tongue with your primitive bile!
但那确实是英语
But that's English!
你们听到了吗 -是英语
Can you hear English? Yeah. English.
错不了
Definitely English.
我只说西格拉克斯语
I speak only Sycoraxic!
如果我听到的是英语
If I can hear English,
那一定是被翻译过
then it's being translated,
也就是说起作用了 那么
which means it's working, which means...
想我了吗
Did you miss me?
你这样会弄伤别人眼睛的
You could have someone's eye out with that!
你胆敢…
How dare...
你就是不明白
You just can't get the staff.
你现在先等着 我很忙
Now you, just wait! I'm busy.
米奇 你好
Mickey, hello!
哈丽叶特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
And Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
天呐 这就像电视剧
Blimey, it's like This Is Your Life.
茶 这就是我需要的 一杯热茶
Tea! That's all I needed, good cup of tea,
过热的自游基和丹宁酸
a superheated infusion of free radicals and tannin.
用来治愈神经键
Just the thing to heal the synapses. Now...
现在 先说最重要的
Now. First things first.
实话告诉我
Be honest...
我看起来怎么样
How do I look? Um...
变了
Different.
变好了还是变坏了
Good different or bad different?
就是变了
Just different.
我是不是…
Am I...
红头发
ginger?
不是 只是有点棕色
No, you're just sort of brown.
我想要红发 从没有试过红发
I wanted to be ginger. I've never been ginger.
洛斯·泰勒 真有你的 你竟敢抛弃我
And you, Rose Tyler, fat lot of good you were! You gave up on me.
这样好没礼貌
Ooh, that's rude.
我现在变成这样了 我很没礼貌吗
Is that the sort of man I am now? Am I rude?
既没礼貌又不是红发
Rude and not ginger?
不好意思 他是谁
I'm sorry, who is this?
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
他是博士
He's the Doctor.
我的博士呢
What happened to my Doctor?
难道只是一个头衔 世代相传的
Or is it a title that's just passed on?
我就是他 如假包换
I'm him. I'm literally him.
同一个人 新的面孔
Same man, new face.
全身上下都是新的
Well, new everything.
但是你不可能
But you can't be...
哈丽叶特·琼斯 我们被困唐宁街
Harriet Jones. We were trapped in Downing Street,
最令你担心的不是外星人
and the thing that scared you wasn't the aliens,
不是战争
wasn't the war,
而是你独自在家的母亲
it was the thought of your mother being on her own.
天呐
Oh, my God!
你赢了大选吗
Did you win the election?
一面倒获胜
Landslide majority.
容我打断一下
If I might interrupt...
对不起 你好 大块头
Yes, sorry. Hello, big fella.
你是谁
Who exactly are you?
这真是个问题
Well, that's the question.
我要知道你是谁
I demand to know who you are!
我不知道
I don't know!
问题是 我是博士
That's the thing. I'm the Doctor,
但除此之外 我就是不知道
but beyond that, I just don't know.
我真的不知道自己是谁
I literally do not know who I am.
一切都未经测试 我幽默吗
It's all untested. Am I funny?
我毒舌吗 性感吗
Am I sarcastic? Sexy?
一切都是谜 生命和灵魂
A right old misery? Life and soul?
左撇子还是右撇子
Right handed, left handed?
赌徒 斗士 懦夫
A gambler, a fighter, a coward,
背叛者 骗子 疯子
a traitor, a liar, a nervous wreck?
照目前的证据看来 我话多倒是真的
Judging by the evidence, I've certainly got a gob.
当我看到这个时 我会怎么做呢
And how am I going to react when I see this?
一个可怕的大按钮
A great big threatening button.
A Great Big Threatening Button
无论任何情况千万不能按下去 对吗
Which Must Not Be Pressed Under Any Circumstances, am I right?
让我猜猜 这是某种控制主体
Let me guess, it's some sort of control matrix.
等等 下面有什么
Hold on, what's feeding it?
看我找到了什么
What have we got here?
血液
Blood?
没错 是人血
Definitely blood, human blood,
A+型 带点铁质
A Positive, with just a dash of iron.
那就是 血液控制
But that means... Blood control.
血液控制 许多年没见过了
Blood control! Oh, I haven't seen blood control for years!
你控制了所有A+血型的人
You're controlling all the A Positives!
这下就给我们带来了一个大问题
Which leaves us with a great big stinking problem.
我真的不知道我是谁
Cos I really don't know who I am.
不知道应该何时停止
I don't know when to stop.
所以 当我看到一个绝对不能按的可怕的大按钮时
So if I see a great big threatening button, which should never, ever, ever be pressed,
我就想这样做
then I just wanna do this!
不要
No!
我为什么在这里
What the hell am I doing up here?
离边缘远点
Get away from the edge!
你杀了他们
You killed them!
你觉得呢 大块头 他们死了吗
What d'you think, big fella? Are they dead?
我们容许他们活下去
We allow them to live.
容许 你别无他法
Allow?! You've no choice!
这就是血液控制 一种低级的巫术
That's all blood control is, a cheap bit of voodoo.
挺吓人的 但仅此而已
Scary, but that's it.
就像催眠
It's like hypnosis.
催眠能让人模仿小鸡走路 或者学猫王唱歌
You can hypnotise someone to walk like a chicken or singing like Elvis.
但你不能催眠他们去死
but you can't hypnotise them to death.
求生的本能太强了
Survival instinct's too strong.
血液控制只是征服的一个手段
Blood control was just one form of conquest.
我能召来舰队 以武力夺下地球
I can summon the Armada and take this world by force.
对 没错 你当然可以这样做
Yeah, you could. You could do that, course you could.
但为什么呢
But why?!
看看他们 这些人类
Look at these people. These human beings.
想想他们的潜能
Consider their potential.
从他们来到地球的一刻
From the day they arrive on the planet,
慢慢迈向太阳
and blinking step into the sun,
还有无数的未知等待他们去发现
there is more to see than can ever be seen,
还有很多… 等等
more to do than... No, hold on.
对不起 那是狮子王的台词
Sorry, that's the Lion King.
但观点仍然是成立的
But the point still stands.
放过他们
Leave them alone.
不然怎样
Or what?
不然
Or...
我挑战你
I challenge you!
看来反响挺热烈的
Ohh, that's struck a chord.
我说得对吗
Am I right that
战斗的神圣法则还有用吗
the sanctified rules of combat still apply?
你要为这个星球而战
You stand as this world's champion?
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道自己是谁
I've no idea who I am,
但你刚替我说出来了
but you've just summed me up.
你接受我的挑战吗
D'you accept my challenge
还是说你只是一个懦夫
or are you just a cranak pel casackree salvak?
为了这个星球
For the planet?
For the planet!
小心
Look out!
真有用 好像我不知道要小心似的
Yeah, that helps. I wouldn't have thought of that.
需要点新鲜空气吗
Bit of fresh air?
退后
Stay back!
你们干预决斗的话 他就自动获胜
Invalidate the challenge and he wins the planet.
你砍断了我的手
You've cut my hand off!
现在我知道自己是谁了
And now I know what sort of man I am.
我是幸运儿 因为非常巧的是
I'm lucky. Cos quite by chance,
我还处于15小时的重生周期内
I'm still within the first 15 hours of my regeneration cycle,
也就是说 我恰好还有足够的残余能量
which means I've got just enough residual cellular energy
来做这个
to do this.
妖术
Witchcraft.
是时间领主
Time Lord.
博士
Doctor!
我还是博士
So I'm still the Doctor, then?
我没有异议
No arguments from me!
你知道最棒的是什么吗
Wanna know the best bit?
这只新手
This new hand...
是一只战斗的手
It's a fighting hand!
我赢了
I win.
杀了我吧
Then kill me.
如果你听从冠军的要求 我就饶了你
I'll spare your life if you'll take this champion's command.
离开地球
Leave this planet,
永不回来
and never return.
怎么样
What do you say?
好
Yes.
以你种族的鲜血发誓
Swear on the blood of your species!
我发誓
I swear.
这就行了 谢谢
There we are. Thanks for that.
再见 大块头
Cheers, big fella.
太棒了
Bravo!
对 太棒了
That says it all. Bravo!
对一个穿着睡衣的人来说很不错
Not bad for a man in his jim-jams.
就像登特 他可是一个好人
Very Arthur Dent. Now there was a nice man.
等等 这是什么
Hold on, what have I got in here?
小蜜桔
A satsuma!
你妈妈的那个朋友 真的很贪吃啊
That friend of your mother's, he does like his snacks.
但圣诞节不就是这样
Doesn't that just sum up Christmas?
你拆了所有礼物
You go through all those presents,
直到最底下
and right at the end,
最后总有一个傻乎乎的小蜜桔藏在那里
tucked away at the bottom, there's always one stupid old satsuma.
谁会想要小蜜桔
Who wants a satsuma?
没有第二个机会 我就是这样的人
No second chances. I'm that sort of a man.
根据古老的决斗法则
By the ancient rites of combat,
我要求你们永远不得侵犯这里
I forbid you to scavenge here for the rest of time.
当你们回到群星之间 请告诉你们的族人
And when you go back to the stars and tell others of this planet,
告诉他们地球的富强
when you tell them of its riches,
告诉他们人类的潜力
its people, its potential...
当你们说起地球时
When you talk of the Earth,
请记得告诉他们
make sure that you tell them this -
这里由我守护
it is defended.
这是哪里
Where are we?
在布洛克汉附近
We're just off Bloxham Road.
我们就在街角 我们回来了
We're just round the corner. We did it!
等等
Wait a minute.
快走 太好了
Go on, my son! Oh, yes!
不要回来
Yes, don't come back!
地球有防卫
It is defended!
我的博士
My Doctor.
我的首相
Prime Minister!
绝对还是原来的博士
Absolutely the same man.
外面还有更多吗
Are there many more out there?
不仅西格拉克斯
Not just Sycorax.
还有千千万万种别的种族
Hundreds of species, thousands of 'em.
人类不断引起外星人的注意
And the human race is drawing attention to itself.
你们不停地发送各种探测器 各种信号
Every day, you're sending out probes, messages and signals.
这个星球非常吵闹
This planet's so noisy.
你们正在被越来越多种族注意到
You're getting noticed. More and more.
赶快习惯吧
You'd better get used to it.
洛斯 -妈妈
Rose! Mum!
麻烦到了
Talking of trouble.
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
他成功了 妈妈
We did it, mum!
你也一样 是你的茶弄好了他的脑袋
You did it too! It was the tea! Fixed his head!
正是我需要的 一杯茶
That's all I needed! Cup of tea!
我就说过 -你看看他
I said so! And look at him!
是他吗 他真的是博士吗
Is it him, though? Is it really the Doctor?
天呐 那是首相啊
Oh, my God, it's the bleedin' Prime Minister!
过来
Come here,
你好点了吗
Are you better?
收到火炬木的讯息
It's a message from Torchwood.
他们说准备好了
They say they're ready.
你们竟然丢下我 我拿着一大堆食物
You left me. Sorry. And I had all the food!
叫他们发射
Tell them to fire.
自由开火
Fire at will.
那是什么 怎么回事
What is that? What's happening?
这是谋杀
That was murder.
这是防卫
That was defence.
根据外星科技改良的
It's adapted from alien technology,
十年前掉到地球的太空船
a ship that fell to Earth ten years ago.
但他们正要离开
But they were leaving!
你自己也说过 博士
You said yourself, Doctor,
他们会回去提起地球的事
they'd go back to the stars and tell others about the Earth.
很抱歉 博士 但你不是长驻地球
I'm sorry, Doctor, but you're not here all the time.
你总是来去匆匆
You come and go.
就在今天
It happened today.
利维先生与少校被杀害了
Mr Llewellyn and the Major, they were murdered,
他们就死在我眼前 在你沉睡的时候
they died right in front of me while you were sleeping.
因此 我们必须要保卫自己
In which case, we have to defend ourselves.
英国的黄金时代
Britain's golden age.
不是没有代价的
It comes with a price.
我给了他们错误的警告
I gave them the wrong warning.
我应该叫他们快跑 跑的越快越好
I should have told them to run, as fast as they can,
躲的远远的 因为怪物来了
run and hide. Because the monsters are coming.
就是人类
The human race.
人类是我的种族 我是站在人类的立场这样做的
Those are the people I represent. I did it on their behalf.
我应该阻止你
And I should have stopped you.
博士 那样你成了什么
What does that make you, Doctor?
另一个外星威胁
Another alien threat?
别挑衅我 哈丽叶特·琼斯
Don't challenge me, Harriet Jones.
我是一个全新的人了
Cos I'm a completely new man.
我用一个字就能扳倒你的政府
I could bring down your government with a single word.
你是我见过最了不起的人
You're the most remarkable man I've ever met.
但我不认为你办得到
But I don't think you're quite capable of that.
说得对 不是一个字
No, you're right. Not a single word.
只要六个
Just six.
我不信 -六个字
I don't think so. Six words.
住口 -六个
Stop it. Six.
她是不是老了
Don't you think she looks tired?
他说了什么
What did he say?
没什么
Nothing really
他说了什么
What did he say?!
没什么 我不知道
Nothing, I don't know...
博士 你到底
Doctor! What did you...
他到底…他说了什么
What was that? What did he say?
你说了什么 博士
What did you say, Doctor?! Doctor!
对不起
I'm sorry.
看 是哈丽叶特·琼斯
Look, it's Harriet Jones!
首相 你是否无力胜任首相一职
Is it true you're no longer fit to be in position?
不 能否谈谈别的话题
No. Can we talk about other things?
你的健康无法再担任公职吗
Is it true you're unfit for office?
我的健康没有不妥
There is nothing wrong with my health.
不知道这些谣传是怎么来的
I don't know where these stories are coming from
对我投反对票是不公平的
and a vote of no confidence is unjustified
你会辞职吗
Will you resign?
一如既往 我很好 很好
On today of all days, I'm fine. I'm fine!
看看我 我内外都很好
Look at me! I'm fine! I look fine, I feel fine.
是贝芙 她叫我们到外面看看
It's Bev. She says, "Go and look outside."
为什么
Why?
不知道 出去看看就是 来吧
I dunno, just go outside and look. Come on, shift!
真美
That's beautiful.
这些是什么 是流星吗
What are they, meteors?
是太空船 散落在大气中
It's the spaceship. Breaking up in the atmosphere.
这不是雪 是灰烬
This isn't snow, it's ash.
那就不美了
OK, not so beautiful.
这是崭新的地球
And this is a brand-new Planet Earth.
现在无法否认外星人的存在了
No denying the existence of aliens now,
所有人都看到了
everyone saw it.
一切都焕然一新
Everything's new.
你呢
What about you?
你有什么打算
What are you gonna do next?
回塔迪斯
Back to the TARDIS.
过从前的生活
Same old life.
一个人吗 -你要来吗
On your own? Don't you want to come?
好啊
Well, yeah.
你肯定 -是的
Do you, though? Yeah.
我以为…因为我变样了
I just thought... Cos I changed.
我以为你变样了
I thought, cos you changed,
你可能不需要我了
you might not want me any more.
我很希望你来的 -好
I'd love you to come. OK!
你永远都不会留下来 对不对
You're never gonna stay, are you?
外面的世界非常广阔
There's just so much out there.
太多可以见识 我必须
So much to see. I've got to.
对
Yeah.
你们真是疯了
I reckon you're mad.
你们两个
The pair of you.
好像就是喜欢追着麻烦走
It's like you go looking for trouble.
麻烦只是小小的插曲
Trouble's just the bits in between.
精彩的都在外面等着我们
It's all waiting out there, Jackie
一切都是崭新的
Everything's brand-new to me,
各种行星 各种生物 不同的视野
all those planets, creatures and horizons.
我都还没看到过
I haven't seen them yet,
没用这只眼睛看到
not with these eyes.
这一切肯定…
And it is gonna be...
美妙极了
Fantastic!
你的手还是让我毛骨悚然
That hand of yours still gives me the creeps.
我们要先去哪里
So, where are we gonna go first?
那里 不 等等
Um... .that way. No, hold on.
那边 -那儿吗
That way. That way?
好吗
D'you think?
好 就去那里
Yeah, that way.
我们要去哪儿 -比最远还要远的地方
Where are we going? Further than we've ever gone.
下季预告
我们没有见过面吧 -我是博士
I don't believe we've met. I'm the Doctor.
请让我介绍莎拉简·史密斯小姐
May I introduce Miss Sarah Jane Smith?
K9
他说他会向漫游者说话 那个无家可归的人
He said he'll talk to a wanderer, to the man without a home.
我向你介绍尊贵的陛下 维多利亚女王
Might I introduce Her Majesty, Queen Victoria.
把她还给我
Give her back to me.
子弹是阻止不了它的
Bullets can't stop it.